<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>333vinyl</title>
    <atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://333vinyl.us</link>
    <description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl 101: Fall Edition</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_saddest_the_baddest_002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_saddest_the_baddest_002/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m Sophie from Whidbey Island in Washington State and I like to pretend I know what’s cool. My music taste is pretty broad so I won’t go into detail, but I will say I like Dave Matthews Band in a very un-ironic way. Here’s what to listen to while smoking, painting nails, and driving home at 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Autre Ne Veut
Song: Counting
Album: Anxiety
Label: Mexican Summer
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Counting,” by Brooklyn producer Arthur Ashin (his name only revealed to fans recently, as to protect his identity during his studies in psychology for his masters degree), easily stands out as the most powerful track off of Autre Ne Veut’s February 2013 album Anxiety. Ashin’s delicate falsetto sets him apart from the sea of “bedroom R&amp;amp;B” producers, as well as his use of honking horn section squeaks and heavy groans that make up the underlying beat of “Counting”; so deep they feel almost pelvic. “Counting” is about ends—in particular, the death of Ashin’s grandmother. The falsetto cries out that &lt;code&gt;I’m counting on the idea that you’ll stay alive&lt;/code&gt; and now you understand the pain behind the lyrics, as well as the catharsis behind the anguish turned into soaring vocals and electronic trills. &lt;code&gt;This is not your time to make it out&lt;/code&gt; screams Ashin, imploring vitality to continue in this relationship, in this life, in this season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Dum Dum Girls
Song: There Is A Light That Never Goes Out
Album: He Gets Me High EP
Label: Sub Pop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will refrain from claiming to like this cover of The Smiths’ joyful lamentation better than the original, but it definitely comes close. Leading lady Kristen “Dee Dee” Gundred’s voice is expansive and elastic. The solid strumming of the guitars are unbound and grinding. Gundred’s cover is almost more emotional than the never-outdone Morrissey. I can sense a bit of anger within her soft growl, but when it’s time for the chorus, the famous &lt;code&gt;And if a ten ton truck kills the both of us // to die by your side well the pleasure, the privilege is mine&lt;/code&gt;, the sentiment is soft and lovely, and infuses the melody with the utmost beauty. The guitars concede to the poetry of the song itself and to the vocals of the Dum Dum Girls, which have been uttered with a quite angelic element. The juxtaposition of these sweet female voices with Morrissey’s raw songwriting makes this my song choice for my MP3 player whilst passing my college crush on the way across the quad as a way to feel powerful again under their gaze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Ghost Loft
Song: Seconds
Album: Seconds
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Be there in seconds flat // Just tell me where you at// Everywhere you want to go// I’ve been there before// That means he don&amp;#39;t need to know&lt;/code&gt; These are the opening lines of “Seconds,” by Danny Choi, AKA LA producer Ghost Loft, who has created the ultimate track of nighttime secrecy. The tune itself is straightforward, but it seems to float into the night before the beat comes in. It is steady, and not quite sure of itself, but it evokes the feeling of urban anxiety; essentially fearful and extremely tentative. But the song feels like a journey, possibly to the doorstep of a lover. “Seconds” is dark, yet comforting with the presence of the quiet voice of track, who appeals to the delicacy and urgency of the actions made in the dead of the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: J. Tillman
Song: Earthly Bodies
Album: Year in the Kingdom
Label: Western Vinyl
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I could tell you about how I feel about fall: the severing of ties, the loss, the renewal, the journey into the darkness in order to grow and evolve… but I’m sure you’ve discovered what autumn means for yourself, or have read about it in some article about re-organizing your life in time for winter. Anyway, I first heard “Earthly Bodies” in an airport bathroom while taking my significant other to his flight back to England. Knowing I would not see him for a long time I was clearly a mess. I was wiping my eyes in the mirror and heard &lt;code&gt;Let me lay across your crescent spine // Press my belly to the mountainside&lt;/code&gt;. I conjured up the road trip I had just taken with my love: the lazy day by the river in the middle of the still-snow-capped mountains amid the shade of green only seen in the Northwest. I got home a few hours later and thought about starting over at college soon and about the autumn of the Northeast. “Earthly Bodies” played as I fell asleep dreaming about the cold weather and healing my hurting heart. Four months later, as I sit in my dorm room that over looks the burgundy-colored quad, J. Tillman’s ballad to transformation, love lost and found in the pleasure of connections to people and nature, and finding comfort within another person still plays. The fall season continues to change me through music, walks in the forest in the glory of Massachusetts, and nostalgia of summer memories with my boyfriend. &lt;code&gt;Baby, lay your head where we begin and end&lt;/code&gt; Tillman sings, asking us through his soft-spoken, wondering-at-the-world poetry that we remember fall is both the end and the start of the cycle of holding on and letting go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eclectic Essentials</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/eclectic_essentials_001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/eclectic_essentials_001/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Sara and I will be contributing to 333vinyl. My taste includes the foundation of indie rock central to the site in addition to special detail to female vocalists and experimental alternative rock. In the interest of saving everyone’s time, let me guide you, the reader, through four albums that I feel represent my basis and growth as a music fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Britney Spears 
Album: Blackout 
Released: 2007
 First listen: 2007
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not think I am beginning our relationship on the wrong foot, dear reader. Truly, pop music was the first cement poured into my malleable ears, and it has stuck with me since. My previous music reviews have all been for contemporary pop albums, including Spears’ 2011 album &lt;em&gt;Femme Fatale&lt;/em&gt;. In addition, &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; taught me not to judge an album by its artist. Publicity for the album occurred during Spears’ highly publicized personal struggles, heavily affecting sales. This did not stop me from receiving a copy from my obsessed best friend, who told me to give her a chance. The first lesson that &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; taught me was to take risks when choosing what music to listen to and to shirk preconceptions and previous opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve explained myself: Blackout is a good album. A damn good album, at that. You would think because the only single that truly took off was the controversial “Gimme More”, which was (and is) treated as a joke by the press, the entire album is brainless pop litter. But it’s truly the opposite: &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; is revolutionary electro-pop that showcases techniques later adopted and brought into the mainstream by other artists. Most notable is the dubstep-influenced breakdown in “Freakshow,” a full four years before another’s appearance in her record-breaking #1 “Hold It Against Me.” Spears is referred to as the Princess of Pop for a reason—she continually works with producers who break the boundaries and with whom she makes pop history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Snow Patrol 
Album: Final Straw 
Released: 2003 
First listen: 2009
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I was turned on to indie rock. My first introduction to the genre was Death Cab for Cutie’s “I Will Possess Your Heart,” which lead me to pursue like-minded artists. Both Death Cab and Snow Patrol had songs on in Wicker Park, a critically-panned film with an incredible motion picture soundtrack. It was there that I discovered pre-“Chasing Cars” Snow Patrol through “How to Be Dead,” a poignant introduction to the kinds of feelings that lead vocalist and songwriter Gary Lightbody evokes. &lt;em&gt;Final Straw&lt;/em&gt; was when I started to identify with lyrics and study the intricacies of them, which is a byproduct of my love for prose in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Fiona Apple
 Album: Extraordinary Machine 
Released: 2005 
First listen: 2010
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before reaching for &lt;em&gt;Extraordinary Machine&lt;/em&gt;, I had listened to Apple’s previous two albums, having been working through her discography. What intrigued me most about &lt;em&gt;Extraordinary Machine&lt;/em&gt; is that two versions of it exist—a leaked bootleg produced exclusively by Jon Brion and sprinkled with strings, and the official release with completely different arrangements on all but two songs and the added “Parting Gift.” The politics behind the music industry interest me and Machine is a classic representation of the label screwing the artist. In addition, demo and bootleg recordings fascinate me on a basic level: that which we were never supposed to hear has been taken from the vaults so that we may appreciate its existence. Unreleased works thrown into the mainstream are like poetry in a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: OK Go 
Album: Of the Blue Colour of the Sky
 Released: 2010 
First listen: 2010
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK Go is my favorite band.  It has taken me seven years of exploring music to be able to find a band that represents all that I love about music, and in 2009 I finally found them. Mostly famous for their DIY, one-take music videos, OK Go are also masters of something beautiful: doing whatever the hell they want. After reaching mainstream success with “Here It Goes Again” and much tension, they left their major label and formed their own. Blue Colour is their first independent release and exemplifies their own eclectic taste—funky psychedelics present in “In the Glass” contrast the acoustic beauty of “Last Leaf.” OK Go writes songs about regret, desire, perseverance, and, put succinctly, the essence of life. OK Go represents all that I love about music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, I look forward to exploring my eclectic music taste with 333vinyl. It truly runs the gamut from &lt;code&gt;I struggle for the words and then give up / My head’s up with the birds on the T-hut&lt;/code&gt; (“Spitting Games” – Snow Patrol) to &lt;code&gt;If I got on top, you&amp;#39;re gonna lose your mind&lt;/code&gt; (“Get Naked [I Got a Plan]” – Britney Spears). Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.last.fm/user/maymayyy&quot;&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/saatuna&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yung Lean - Unknown Memory</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/yung_lean-unknown_memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/yung_lean-unknown_memory/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Used to be a hobby now it’s all I think about // That’s what rap does&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yung Lean is undeniably interesting. He first garnered attention with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrQWhFysPKY&quot;&gt;“Ginseng Strip 2002”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=stgrSjynPKs&quot;&gt;“Hurt”&lt;/a&gt;, and while he came off as a goofy swede adopting esoteric internet culture, he was-in the purest form-just a young hip-hop fan. He was an avid listener who, freed from any American preconceptions about rap and lucky enough to be around some incredibly musical producers, just went for it. It worked: they made a great project, established a ravenous fanbase, and garnered internet-wide attention. Lean clearly found his calling and realized he wanted to eschew any association with so-called “meme rap.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tMgkt9jdjTU&quot;&gt;“Kyoto”&lt;/a&gt;, a song that caught doubters off-gaurd. To many, the song still seemed ridiculous, his rapping terrible, and the video over-the-top silly, but to those who had seen “Hurt” saw the metamorphosis. Unknown Memory is the product of this change, the creation of a Yung Lean who unexpectedly became a full-fledged rap star; complete with a sold-out tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gone are many of the nonsensical lines and perpetual non-sequiturs. Yung Lean replaces them with confidence, introspective musings, and braggadocio that–while it was seen as comedic in past work–in many cases can now be assumed true. This is what a lot of the disappointment and negative reactions stem from. Making the switch from quasi-joke rapper to post quasi-joke rapper with more serious songs puts him in limbo–should be compared with traditional rappers? Or should he be lumped with the rappers who get a handicap for being a “meme”? Yung Lean is transitioning, what some could even posture as artistic growth. Shedding mumbling for an auto-tune drawl a la Future does him favors in furthering his confidence, and complements the production fantastically. And that is what Lean is all about, he is yet another instrument to the Yung Gud or the Yung Sherman band which backs him up. In tracks like “Yoshi City” and “Ghosttown” Lean seems most formidable, and these are easily the most “Kyoto”-esque in terms of accessibility. “Ice Cold Smoke” is the most auto-tuned, but with slow skittering hats, a short time stamp, and a fantastic beat switch, it is digestible. Lean succeeds again with infectious choruses–I catch myself singing “Don’t Go” and “Blinded” at various points during the day. However, in songs like “Sandman” and “Volt” the beats are overly busy, and Lean’s raps do not mesh. The instrumental tracks also did nothing but annoy me, and the only purpose I could see them serving would be to either provide a break from Lean’s voice or to jar the listener in preparation for his unorthodox sound. That being said, I liked a good amount of tracks on this album, thought it was a decent project overall, and I appreciate his development. There are a few tracks that will definitely go in rotation for the long term. The over-the-top nature of his previous project, Unknown Death, is lost in Unknown Memory and while it has positive implications, the album lacks some of that original charm by ironically being believable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yung Lean has merit. If you don’t like the rapping or the production, at least appreciate the new concepts of hip-hop he has to bring the the table, the culture that he has appropriated and fashioned into a cult, or simply that he is doing his thing as an 18 year old non-native speaker. This cult of “sadboys” may be doing him no favors in the way that Lil B’s #taskforce annoys the hell out of casual listeners, but he is another interesting case of niche hip-hop and internet fame.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rilo Kiley - The Execution of All Things</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/rilo_kiley-the_execution_of_all_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/rilo_kiley-the_execution_of_all_things/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Sara and I will be contributing to 333vinyl. My taste includes the foundation of indie rock central to the site in addition to special detail to female vocalists and experimental alternative rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is a strange thing. It influences your capacity to create, so creative people tend to go through periods of inactivity. With its terror comes a common ground that all people with depression can fall back upon. This foundation is exemplified in Rilo Kiley’s sophomore album, &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having loss and regret at the forefront of this album made it easy to connect to during one of my own episodes. The opening track, “The Good That Won’t Come Out”, tugs on the bottom of your coat until you’re forced to listen to what it has to say. Right away, vocalist Jenny Lewis attempts to make a connection with the listener: “let’s get together and talk about the modern age.” A desire to stray from stagnation makes its appearance through the album, along with Lewis and co-vocalist Blake Sennett’s personal experiences with depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You say I choose sadness, that it never once has chosen me. Maybe you’re right.” (“The Good That Won’t Come Out”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musically, &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt; is of the standard indie pop rock fare that made its rounds in the early 2000s. It is less inspired by country rock compared to their previous efforts, more so matching the Omaha Sound referenced in the title track “The Execution of All Things”. After all, the record was released off of Saddle Creek Records, founded by Bright Eyes’ frontman Conor Oberst. However, &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt; does continue down the established path of its predecessor by incorporating electronic sounds—not quite the MIDI-like interludes of &lt;em&gt;Take Offs and Landings&lt;/em&gt;, but like the introduction to the title track, an anticipatory build to the reflective prose within. Its frank delivery of lyrics is what makes the album truly unique and what increased their recognition in the scene with their next album, &lt;em&gt;More Adventurous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, similar to the “Variations on a Theme” interludes from their first album, pieces of a song appear throughout the album after “So Long”, “My Slumbering Heart”, and “Spectacular Views”. This song delivered in three parts is named by its last lyric, “And That’s How I Choose to Remember It”. The song is an exposition on the divorce of Lewis’ parents and her childhood that perfectly strings together the album’s motifs and adds to its overall cohesiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lewis was undoubtedly the face of the band (which broke up in 2011); however, there are still two tracks with vocals by Sennett on the album. The stronger of the two is “Three Hopeful Thoughts”, a hard rocking song about the removal of someone from one’s life. There are many goodbyes on this album: to parents, to lovers, to parts of one’s self. The kind of goodbye explored on this song is one that the author is in control of and actively wants, a contrast to the others present. This gives the song and subsequently the album a different kind of hope: a hope that acknowledges the pain of the past but also focuses on the opportunities of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stand-out track on an album filled with poignant insights is also its biggest hit, “A Better Son/Daughter”. It turns the themes of the album to max volume at the most important moment, guiding the listener through the portion of a depressive episode where one realizes they will have to fight and make it through the fog, reminding them that the good may be gone for now but it can still come out of them. &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt; is an essential part of Rilo Kiley’s catalog and a quintessential indie-rock representation of grief.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If We Hung Out</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/if_we_hung_out_002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/if_we_hung_out_002/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second edition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://333vinyl.us/authors/mason-lynaugh.html&quot;&gt;Mason Lynaugh’s&lt;/a&gt; If We Hung Out. This edition features Travi$ Scott, Andrea, and Jimmy Johnson.
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_002/travi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/travisscott-2/04-drugs-you-should-try-it&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travi$ Scott - “Drugs You Should Try It”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Around two weeks ago, Travi$ Scott released a surprise mixtape. Not only was it a surprise in terms of release–he pulled a Beyonce–but it was also surprisingly put together. Travis Scott, an XXL freshman from 2013, has a lot of enemies for good reasons. He first made ripples throughout the blogosphere when he released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vld3uWewvyI&quot;&gt;“Lights”&lt;/a&gt;, and, clearly rife with talent, he continued to generate buzz until he signed a 360 deal as a producer for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KC-1AaTonTs&quot;&gt;G.O.O.D. Music&lt;/a&gt; and a rapper for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2uQfbc3NLz8&quot;&gt;Grand Hustle&lt;/a&gt;. However, his entire career has been marred with scandal. He has been attacked for ragging on T.I. and Jay-Z, two of his collaborators, stealing beats, album artwork, and aggravating fans by heedlessly making and subsequently missing release dates. His debut mixtape “Owl Pharaoh”, was a testament to his nature. It was messy, uneven, and poorly handled, but it provided the listener with glimpses into his mind and his obvious talent behind the mic and the boards. “Drugs You Should Try It” is haunting and magnificent. The auto-tuned wailing adds a shocking amount of humanity to a poignant sample, and Scott’s rapping has made dramatic improvement. The entire mixtape is worth a listen, especially these  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dY5F5EsQwqE&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFbrRXdruv4&quot;&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll find an incredible level of depth to the production, especially in the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_002/andrea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4fhwCvafjYA&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea - “Your Morning”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Anyone who knows me knows that this is one of my all time favorite songs. By a French producer named Andrea (whether that is pronounced anh-drey-ah or ann-dree-ah is beyond me), who is actually not a female, despite the name. To me, it is the perfect morning song (apt title), and the ideal song for a sunny day in a green field. I use it as an alarm on my iPhone because it makes waking up enjoyable, and I have so much nostalgia attached to it that on rough days it can bring up some emotions, ya feel? Sonically, it reminds me of water flowing through a creek. I’m sitting there adjacent two a pair of stones engulfed in moss, and smiling with a childhood friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_002/jimyjohn.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPgcSFO6qOg&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Johnson - “Northside”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For almost a year the Toronto-based rapper Jimmy Johnson and Austin, Texas producer Eric Dingus have been making relatively silent moves above the border. Affiliated with the label “Prime”, Johnson and Dingus have been inching into the inner circle of Drake’s imprint OVO, and with the title of Drake’s 4th studio effort inspired by Jimmy Johnson, popularizer of the term “The 6”, it seems they have cemented their place. Jimmy Johnson is a fairly middle of the line rapper, but when he combines his vocals with auto-tune and a signature Dingus beat, he does what many auto-tune proficinatos does and becomes more of an instrument than an MC. “Northside” is his best effort yet, with a gritty beat and an infectious chorus, while his debut mixtape some has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j-4uWvz3bJk&quot;&gt;gems&lt;/a&gt; as well (the mixtape is fairly good and is definitely worth a few listens). Dingus as well, is someone to watch. I give him until Drake’s next album (which I assume will include his production) to blow up even more than he already has. After &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/octobers-very-own-presents-haw-eric-dingus-mixtape&quot;&gt;performing&lt;/a&gt; at OVO’s Houston Appreciation Weekend, and being featured on the OVO blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://octobersveryown.blogspot.com/2013/11/drake-worst-behavior-eric-dingus-remix.html&quot;&gt;multiple times&lt;/a&gt;, his remixes are getting serious traffic. His label, Dream Sequence Records, is working on assembling a roster and already has reached some &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/dream-sequence-records/dowrong-shooters-prod-eric&quot;&gt;talent&lt;/a&gt;. Jimmy Johnson and Eric Dingus should definitely be on your radar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl During the Summer 101</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_saddest_the_baddest_001/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_saddest_the_baddest_001/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m Sophie from Whidbey Island in Washington State and I like to pretend I know what’s cool. My music taste is pretty broad so I won’t go into detail, but I will say I like Dave Matthews Band in a very un-ironic way. Here’s what to listen to while smoking, painting nails, and driving home at 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The War On Drugs
Song: Red Eyes
Album: Lost In The Dream
Label: Secretly Canadian
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Red Eyes is the breakout song from what I might call one of the best albums of the year so far from Philadelphia’s The War On Drugs. Solely written by vocalist Adam Grandciel after a heartbreak, Lost In the Dream is expansive, lofty and filled with desire and melancholic beauty. Red Eyes is reminiscent of Springsteen craftsmanship: passion fueled vocal bursts and shouts, jangling piano chords, grinding crescendo leading to the chorus. The song signifies the end of a relationship, but it remains resiliently optimistic and almost elated. “I can see it in the darkness coming my way… Well we’re here” concludes Grandciel, the relationship at it’s close, as the song triumphantly rings out into the night; the soundtrack to a drive through the desert of self discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The Radio Dept.
Song: Heaven’s On Fire
Album: Clinging To A Scheme
Label: Labrador
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Swedish electro-pop trio’s most popular release is their most unusual record, and probably their most satirical. The track opens with a segment from Sonic Youth frontman Thurston Moore, who so boldly decries pop culture, capitalism, and even calls the youth to action to destroy this “bogus” society. And yet, through Moore’s last statements can be heard the openings of The Radio Dept.’s bubbling, frothy pink pop song almost mockingly piercing with their sweetness the sentiments of the political statement. It is the bands one and only take on a modern pop anthem, complete with the line “One look at you, and heaven’s on fire” breathed out into the waves and jingles of the track; a playful love song contrasted only by the opening statements. This song is summer in the the most innocent and quintessential means possible, yet the irony of singer Johan Ducanson’s counter phrase “One look at you, and hell’s on fire” and Thurston Moore’s opening interview leave the foaming keyboard barbed with hilarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Mac DeMarco
Song: Ode To Viceroy
Album: 2
Label: Captured Tracks
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mac DeMarco is your typical stoner/slacker friend. Plaid shirt, scruffy smirk on his wide mouthed smile, and the inability to actually like anything in his life without a hint of sarcasm. However, this love song to DeMarco’s smoke of choice is the most un-ironic sentimentality you will hear from him. “Oh honey, I’ll smoke you ’til I’m dying” sighs DeMarco, as he coos over his beloved destruction, as his guitar soars sharply into the suburban night, or at the corner store “already running dry” or as the evening starts to dim the sky. DeMarco swears eternal faithfulness as he tenderly strums out his promises over the drums, never faltering, just like his love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Lana Del Rey
Song: Sad Girl
Album: Ultraviolence
Label: Polydor, Interscope
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes. No reference to teenage angst would be complete without a little Lana. Really, the entirety of Del Rey’s Ultraviolence could be on this list. The album is really not too different from 2012’s Born To Die, and although the hip hop influences from her earlier work are replaced with Dan Auberbach’s (The Black Keys) spaced out guitar solos and jazz effects, Del Rey still is heartbroken, struggling to achieve the irresistible American Dream, and setting out to prove once again that she’s not like “the other girls”. And although these themes are getting quite annoying, every single track on the album is stunning. But Sad Girl is Del Rey’s theme, filled to the top with rage repressed into beautiful longing, lovers who cannot be loved, floating vocals, and all the cinematic accompaniment that can be met with Del Rey’s whining “I’m a sad girl, a bad girl”. She’ll go to her grave defending her man even though his “bonnie on the side” makes her a sad, sad girl, and you just wouldn’t understand. Yet millions of pimpled faced adolescents who haven’t even moved out of the house still croon her ballads. This is perfection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Pornographers - Brill Bruisers</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_new_pornographers-brill_bruisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_new_pornographers-brill_bruisers/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the best New Pornographers album since &lt;em&gt;Twin Cinema&lt;/em&gt;. The Canadian supergroup excels in celebratory music, and after two somewhat-lackluster offerings with a darker sound, &lt;em&gt;Brill Bruisers&lt;/em&gt; is a triumphant return. Frontman A.C. Newman described the record as “a celebration record,” and the band follows through completely on that promise, boasting titles like “Champions of Red Wine” and “Dancehall Domine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album begins with the title track, a single with a masterful ear-worm of a wordless chorus. Two lighter celebratory songs follow that sound like they could be from earlier New Pornographers albums, “Champions of Red Wine” and “Fantasy Fools.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next comes my personal favorite track, “War on the East Coast.” Its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WMcumbSMY_8&quot;&gt;brilliant 90s-Britpop-style video&lt;/a&gt; combined with Dan Bejar’s unique vocal stylings make for four minutes of up-tempo bliss. It’s one of those songs that feels like you’ve been waiting to hear for a long time. The song transitions smoothly into “Backstairs,” which starts with slow, vocoder vocals but eventually breaks out into one of the band’s grooviest verses. Neko Case’s golden voice propels along the following “Marching Orders,” which concludes one of the strongest trios the band has recorded. “Another Drug Deal of the Heart” serves as a quick, fun epilogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that there aren’t a few misses on the album. “Born With a Sound,” another Bejar track, sounds a lot like a watered-down “War on the East Coast.” The following “Wide Eyes” has its moments but largely falls flat, with the band coming across as a New Pornographers cover band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, “Dancehall Domine” is the band doing what they do best, and has a classic New Pornographers sound. “Spidyr” is a bit of an oddball, but fits in well with “Hi-Rise,” both providing a lush respite from the celebrations. Closer “You Tell Me Where” is a hopeful song, and provides a perfect refrain to end the album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;em&gt;Brill Bruisers&lt;/em&gt; never quite reaches the highs of &lt;em&gt;Mass Romantic&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Electric Version&lt;/em&gt;, it’s the best New Pornographers record in a long time, and it’s a great album for celebration. It’s a triumphant return for a triumphant band.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If We Hung Out</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mason Lynaugh and I will occasionally be contributing to 333vinyl. My musical tastes include Ben’s, but are more concerned with the most recent developments in hip hop - whether it be drill, coastal, trap, or slip-hop - so I will focus mainly on what has been blaring through my speakers on its path to being overplayed. I’m planning on doing periodical entries under the terrible title “if we hung out” because “songs I would make you listen to if we hung out” was a bit worse, and the people who do hang out with me would attest to its accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/kanye.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4NTDoPQ4mU&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kanye West - All Day (Remake)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A triumphant victory for the lovely people over at KTT (or &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/ktt.jpg&quot;&gt;KanyeToThe&lt;/a&gt;, a forum I endearingly refer to as the 4chan of hip hop) came the day in which someone announced they had a leak of the impending single from Kanye’s untitled seventh solo album. Ironically, this “leak” with the sound quality of something recorded on a graphing calculator triggered an infuriated Kanye to retreat back to Mexico and re-record for an album already rumored to be complete. Nonetheless, since I am part of that seeming minority that doesn’t mind Kanye’s rants, debauchery, or wife, and enjoys his music, I love this remake. Despite being full of mumbling, filler freestyle, unfinished lines, and of shoebox audio quality, it still bumps in the whip, dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/ilm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HRQyg8RHvIQ&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I LOVE MAKONNEN - I Don’t Sell Molly No More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: ILM has recently received an unprecedented amount of attention for a singer who wails over beats churned out by ATL’s trap oligarchy while &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foxylounge.com/IMG/jpg/i_love_makonnen_tumblr_mcxyf4addm1qlcgcbo1_500-2.jpg&quot;&gt;undeniably resembling a plush toy in appearance&lt;/a&gt;. This is result of current king of rap Drake remixing his fantastic song &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/makonnen-ft-drake-tuesday&quot;&gt;“Club Going Up On A Tuesday”&lt;/a&gt;.  “I Don’t Sell” is a grimy gem amongst ballads about mutual infidelity from his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hotnewhiphop.com/ilovemakonnen-i-love-makonnen-ep-new-mixtape.114225.html&quot;&gt;self-titled EP&lt;/a&gt;, and is one of those songs that people “listen to as a joke” but show definite signs of enjoyment when it is played (think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxLS-cpgbe0&quot;&gt;“Dolce and Gabanna”&lt;/a&gt;). I personally love ILM and look forward to his growth as an artist now that he has garnered some limelight a la &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OmHW9IzZYzU&quot;&gt;Migos&lt;/a&gt;. No, I don’t care that you think he sounds like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iq_d8VSM0nw&quot;&gt;IceJJFish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/rustie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mO2VcJAkOw&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rustie - Attak (feat. Danny Brown)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: This is one of those songs that you may have already burnt out on if you’re a self-identifying “hip hop head”, into the contemporary EDM scene, or someone who lurks on Soundcloud. “Attak” marks the fourth collaboration between the two, and I see it as rivaling the incredible &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=22eSJgqxnX4&quot;&gt;“Side B (Dope Song)”&lt;/a&gt; in quality. If you like Danny Brown, Rustie, Electronic music, and/or rap (that should be most everyone), this might tickle your pickle a little. Definitely a party starter up there with the Young Thug cut &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=34LyiriE6eo&quot;&gt;“Old English”&lt;/a&gt; (also a must-listen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/mustard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howflyhiphop.com/2014/08/11/dj-mustard-face-down-download-mp3-lil-wayne-big-sean/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face down (feat. Lil Wayne, Lil Boosie, Big Sean, YG)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Say what you will about DJ Mustard, I stand by my position that he has carved a ubiquitous sound and is deserving of all success. Some may get annoyed by the “aye aye aye” and the way that he uses the same sample kit across his entire discography, but those sounds have some parasitic quality that will infect its way to the top 40. “Face Down” comes from his rudimentary debut album 10 Summers, yet is anything but. It’s a classic love story - “she like her ass tooted up and her face down” with yet another verse from a Lil Wayne who is making admirable progress in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmddPo_c2oE&quot;&gt;proving he’s still got it&lt;/a&gt;. However, the real standout here is Big Sean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Oh my God, I’m in love with a porn star
I’m in love with a foreign car, they both topless
I done tricked off a gold Rolle wrist watch
Man, I’m tired of dealing with these h--- but my d--- not
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/mensa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5jUGAVUwhRU&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Down On My Luck - Vic Mensa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: By this point everyone knows Disclosure from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93ASUImTedo&quot;&gt;“Latch”&lt;/a&gt;, but this Disclosure-produced song hasn’t gotten the love it deserves. I have trouble determining whether it’s alliance lies with EDM or rap, but those familiar with Vic Mensa know how his catalog dabbles in expansive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZLp7M5SMBkQ&quot;&gt;sonic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gbcyfRztHmw&quot;&gt;palettes&lt;/a&gt;. “Down On My Luck” is coupled with a clever Groundhog Day-inspired music video that serves as the cherry on top of one of my favorite jams for late drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/if_we_hung_out_001/trae.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2IfOEp5iyE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trae Tha Truth - Try Me (feat. Young Thug)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: I think Young Thug is the most interesting rapper making noise right now, and he is my second favorite rapper (behind Drake). He’s doing things that are just weird, and reaching commercial success &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5-0kZ_jeIHI&quot;&gt;where other oddballs like Lil B couldn’t&lt;/a&gt;. His charisma and shrill, drawling flow permeate through a song until he owns it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=etfIdtm-OC8&quot;&gt;whether he is “featured” or not&lt;/a&gt;. Case in point, “Try Me” shows Young Thug partnering with the typically forgettable H-town hero to craft a contender for banger of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I've Been Listening To</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/listening_to_001/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/listening_to_001/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I finally went through a large portion of all the albums on my “to-listen” list. These are the ones I’m currently enjoying. Interestingly enough, seven of the nine albums are debuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img id=&quot;collage&quot; src=&quot;collage.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach House - &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a great album that took me a few listens to get in to. It’s not groundbreaking, but it’s incredible high-quality and accessible dream pop. Good for sunrises, sunsets, and dusk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIIV - &lt;em&gt;Oshin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Maybe the best way to describe this album is a rainy day at the beach. Great dreamy jam sound, reminiscient of Real Estate. “Doused” is a standout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Jesus and Mary Chain - &lt;em&gt;Psychocandy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Slacker shoegaze, or shoegaze before there was shoegaze. The JAMC’s noisy guitars and airy vocals paved the way for My Bloody Valentine just three years later. And they didn’t care. This is some of the catchiest and most indifferent noise you can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joy Division - &lt;em&gt;Unknown Pleasures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the best post-punk albums. Ian Curtis’ baritone matches perfectly with the themes of isolation prevalent in his lyrics. The guitar and bass propell the songs through they airy abyss created by the drums. I’m going to listen to the follow-up &lt;em&gt;Closer&lt;/em&gt; soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metric - &lt;em&gt;Old World Underground, Where Are You Now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Metric’s debut album. It sounds a lot different from their later work, but it has a good punk vibe. Creates a unique nervous atmosphere. I think it’s about robots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rapture - &lt;em&gt;Echoes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the first true dance-punk albums. The Rapture also experiment with modern indie rock. Highlights include the Strokes-esque title track and lead single “House of Jealous Lovers.” Definitely check this out if you’re into dance-punk or early 2000s garage rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ride - &lt;em&gt;Nowhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: This album is possibly the best that shoegaze has to offer outside of My Bloody Valentine. Opener “Seagull” is iconic, and the other tracks that fill out the album’s short 39-minute runtime are almost as good. More accessible than some of the other popular shoegaze albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonic Youth - &lt;em&gt;Daydream Nation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: “Teen Age Riot” is a masterpiece, the best track on what most say is Sonic Youth’s best work. The album perfectly balances noise and rock, creating a unique sound that new indie acts are still trying to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunny Day Real Estate - &lt;em&gt;Diary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A definitive emo album. Not to be confused with A Sunny Day In Glasgow. Great guitar and vocal work. If you like “In Circles,” you’ll like the album. Perfect for warm summer night listening.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>of Montreal - Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/of_montreal-hissing_fauna,_are_you_the_destroyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/of_montreal-hissing_fauna,_are_you_the_destroyer/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;of Montreal, part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elephant_Six&quot;&gt;Elephant 6 collective&lt;/a&gt; that spawned (among others) Neutral Milk Hotel and The Olivia Tremor Control, has released twelve albums in sixteen years. While not as consistent in quality as, say, Spoon, of Montreal’s substantial output has yielded several magnificent albums. &lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?&lt;/em&gt; is of Montreal’s finest work, an impressive struggle with depression and identity backed by infectious melodies and grooves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This album is a masterpiece. The first half is quintessential quirky indie pop, and the second is glorious glam-pop. The shift is pulled off seamlessly during the album’s twelve-minute centerpiece “The Past Is a Grotesque Animal,” in which Kevin Barnes (who wrote the album himself) transforms into a black transsexual (&lt;code&gt;I got my Georgie Fruit on / He&amp;#39;s a dark mutation / For my demented past time&lt;/code&gt;). He keeps this alter ego for the rest of &lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna&lt;/em&gt; and of Montreal’s next three albums, which are named after the last lines of “Faberge Falls For Shuggie” (&lt;code&gt;Skeletal lamping, the controller sphere, false priest&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album begins with “Suffer For Fashion,” which might be the most straightforwardly catchy song on the album. It has a bit of an early Arcade Fire feel. The next two songs are similarly catchy, trippy indie pop. One of the best tracks on the album is lead single “Heimdalsgate Like a Promethean Curse,” a plea with serotonin to not make Barnes “sick again.” “Gronlandic Edit” and “A Sentence of Sorts in Kongsvinger” deal with depression, isolation, and identity crisis (&lt;code&gt;I spent the winter with my nose buried in a book / While trying to restructure my character / Cause it had become vile to its creator&lt;/code&gt;). “The Past Is A Grotesque Animal” follows directly after, an epic cathartic freakout. From its ashes rises “Bunny Ain’t No Kind Of Rider,” a more lighthearted put-down of a club patron’s come-on (which he shoots down due to her lack of soul power). “Faberge Falls For Shuggie” is of Montreal at its grooviest and trippiest. “Labrynthian Pomp” is another power-glam tour de force, beginning with &lt;code&gt;How you wanna hate a thing / When you are so inferior&lt;/code&gt;. It flows quite nicely into the similar “She’s A Rejector.” “We Were Born the Mutants Again With Leafling” is a slightly calmer, more melodic and thoughtful ending to a fantastic album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnes’ lyrics contain the key to &lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna&lt;/em&gt;‘s success. &lt;code&gt;We just want to emote until we&amp;#39;re dead / I know we suffer for fashion or whatever&lt;/code&gt;, implying that we suffer because it’s fashionable. Barnes is notorious for his dry humor, and it’s at its strongest here. The album features lines such as &lt;code&gt;Saw her at Go kissing girls, what a shock / I said you must be an artist&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Somehow you&amp;#39;ve red-rovered the Gestapo circling my heart&lt;/code&gt; At the same time, he is honest to a fault and inexplicably clever. Throughout the album, Barnes struggles through chemical depression and the deterioration of a relationship, and does so in a brilliant, weird, and yet relatable way. Few songwriters can be as simultaneously odd and familiar as Kevin Barnes, and he is at his best on this album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?&lt;/em&gt; is an essential listen for anyone who has struggled with chemicals, has a dry wit, or just loves damn good indie pop songs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death Cab For Cutie - Transatlanticism</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/death_cab_for_cutie-transatlanticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/death_cab_for_cutie-transatlanticism/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; is widely considered Death Cab For Cutie’s magnum opus. It’s Death Cab’s fourth studio album of seven, but probably the first album that comes to someone’s mind when they talk about the band. “Sound of Settling,” which frontman Ben Gibbard originally didn’t want to include on the album, has become one of Death Cab’s biggest hits. The rough concept album about distance and its effect on relationships is beloved by critics, teenagers, and music enthusiasts alike, and is considered an instant classic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; begins with “The New Year,” which describes Dismemberment-Plan-style disillusionment with new year’s festivities. It sets the tone nicely for what will follow, as does “Lightness,” which flows nicely into the standout “Title and Registration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The song starts with Gibbard cleverly proposing a change of the name “glove compartment,” because the only things inside are disappointment and regret. The drum sound here is instantly memorable, and drives Gibbard’s voice and the equally distinctive riff forward, a common musical theme across &lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Expo ‘86” artfully turns an innocent, pleasant riff into a symbol of grating repetition, all while maintaining its saccharine facade. Lead single “Sound of Settling” is Death Cab at their catchiest, matched only by &lt;em&gt;Plans&lt;/em&gt; single “Crooked Teeth.” It doesn’t fit perfectly with the rest of these songs, but it serves its purpose as a nice introductory point to the band and acts as an upbeat catharsis of sorts before the harder-hitting second half of the album takes over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the album provides some of the strongest tracks, revolving around the titular centerpiece, a beautiful seven-minute treatise against distance and a plea for closeness. By the time “A Lack of Color” comes on, you, like Gibbard, know it’s over but don’t want it to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrow Stairs&lt;/em&gt; was always my favorite Death Cab album until I read along while listening through this. I still maintain the (unpopular) opinion that &lt;em&gt;Narrow Stairs&lt;/em&gt; is Death Cab’s most instrumentally interesting work, but Gibbard’s lyrics on this album push it above and beyond any of the band’s efforts since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; is by no means an uplifting album, but it doesn’t force gloom upon you. Instead, the album sinks inside you, until you come to feel what Death Cab want you to feel. Gibbard doesn’t attempt to hide his true meaning in complex wordplay—in fact, he’s quite happy to spell out what he’s experiencing. He does so artfully however, coming across as earnest instead of inane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you really &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to this album, you begin to know it like a friend. It’s shy at first, but once you strike up a conversation with it, and it tells you all it knows about young love and separation, you don’t want to stop talking. &lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; truly is Death Cab For Cutie at their best. With warm guitar melodies, distinctive drumming, and lyrics that will be scrawled in notebook margins for years to come, it definitely deserves your time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken Social Scene - You Forgot It In People</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/broken_social_scene-you_forgot_it_in_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/broken_social_scene-you_forgot_it_in_people/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took me a few listens to get into &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt;. The first time I downloaded it, I skimmed through the songs. Upon not finding any immediate hits on what was billed as a pop album, I decided to give it a more thorough listen on a later date. Now, nearly a year after first listening to it, I decided to give it another chance, and another, and another. There is so much more to this album than I initially thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the most amazing thing about Broken Social Scene is how many incredible bands the supergroup contains. Members of Metric, Feist, and Stars are all present on &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt;, and it shows. The band manages to put each individual’s talent to good use. This brilliant album is disjointed enough not to be repetitive, but cohesive enough to not lose the listener’s attention, even throughout the several instrumentals that are scattered through the track listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standout tracks here are definitely fan-favorites “Anthems For A Seventeen Year-Old Girl” and “Lover’s Spit.” “Anthems” is a stunning piece, consisting of soft banjo plucks and strings drifting around Emily Haines of Metric’s looping, warped vocals. The repetition is key as Haines rolls through several choice phrases, letting each resonate before pleading &lt;code&gt;Park that car, drop that phone, sleep on the floor, dream about me&lt;/code&gt; again and again until you want to do just that. The phrase gets gently imprinted in your ears, becoming a sort of mantra which stays in your head through the instrumentals which follow shortly after. “Lover’s Spit” is one of the oddest and bitterest ballads in recent memory, and when paired with “Anthems” creates a potent mixture of lonely longing that hasn’t been matched in years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the album doesn’t hit quite as heavily, but when combined with the standout tracks, &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt; is easier to relate to than most pop albums. While so much pop is about common problems, it often feels like the musicians are removed and distant. Here, Broken Social Scene is messaging you late at night, because they know exactly how you feel and they want to let you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what stands out to me the most about &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt; is that Broken Social Scene managed to make music for teenagers without being simplistic. The lyrics oscillate between simple, powerful mantras and dark, visceral, abrasive metaphors, but not once does the album come off as condescending or fake. Instead, Broken Social Scene is holding your hair back when you vomit from drinking too much trying to forget, and laughing with you when you laugh at yourself the next morning. You just want to return the favor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Lovers - The Modern Lovers</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_modern_lovers-the_modern_lovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/the_modern_lovers-the_modern_lovers/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Modern Lovers&lt;/em&gt; starts off with Richman counting &lt;code&gt;1-2-3-4-5-6!&lt;/code&gt;, a twist on the classic four-count that begins so many songs. It’s a little familiar, a little odd, and strangely endearing, all threads that run deep in the band’s definitive proto-punk opus as well as in the work of the countless artists that were inspired by the album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first I heard of The Modern Lovers was James Murphy’s name-drop in “Losing My Edge.” I’ve been working my way through all (well, most) of the bands he mentions, and the Modern Lovers Wikipedia page intrigued me, so I got the album. As soon as the first notes hit, I could tell that I was going to witness something unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album begins with “Roadrunner,” The Modern Lovers’ biggest hit and easily their catchiest song. The groove established on this opening track carries on through the rest of the album, creating a driving force that doesn’t pause until “Hospital.” A lot has been said about this one already, so I’ll just add that it’s one of the best road-trip songs ever written. The second track, “Astral Plane,” sounds like a missed connection in a hazy basement backed by a trademark Modern Lovers seventies groove—the atmosphere the band manages to create here is palpable. Unfortunately, the rest of the tracks don’t stand out as much, especially in comparison to “Roadrunner.” However, the band exchanges a lack of standouts for consistency, and the album is so well-executed that the trade off is worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One key feature of the album is Jerry Harrison’s keyboard. It shows up in all the right places, propelling “Roadrunner,” “Pablo Picasso,” and “Modern World” but hanging back on the guitar-driven “She Cracked” and “Old World.” Bassist Ernie Brooks contributes similarly, displaying the ability to play in several different styles depending on what fits the song best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This album is definitive proto-punk, but what really sets it apart for me is the heart-on-sleeve nature of the lyrics. When Jonathan Richman rants about Picasso’s womanizing ways in the incredibly clever “Pablo Picasso,” (which features the refrain &lt;code&gt;Pablo Picasso never got called an asshole&lt;/code&gt;) you get the sense that Richman has been called an asshole too often. Even when Richman cheesily spells out the title of “Girlfriend,” he sounds earnest and wide-eyed instead of inane. This is particularly impressive considering the nasal sneer he carries throughout the duration of the album, creating a masterful contrast of punk power and pop vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give &lt;em&gt;The Modern Lovers&lt;/em&gt; a listen. It’s a classic collection of strong songs, and there’s never a dull moment. It’s well worth counting past four for the opportunity to experience the roots of punk taking shape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Le Tigre - Le Tigre</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/le_tigre-le_tigre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01  Aug 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/le_tigre-le_tigre/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Le Tigre is perhaps best known as Kathleen Hanna’s other band. Hanna was the frontwoman of Bikini Kill (which kickstarted the riot grrrl movement), has had several documentaries made about her, and (fun-fact) is married to Ad-Rock. But I only heard about Le Tigre yesterday while looking for dance-punk bands. I had no idea Hanna was involved until the first verse of the first (and perhaps best) song, “Deceptacon,” which tears down preconceptions, sets expectations, and takes a shot at pop music in five lines: &lt;code&gt;Wanna disco? / Wanna see me disco? / Let me hear you depoliticize my rhyme. / One! Two! Three! Four! /  You got what you been asking for.&lt;/code&gt; It’s a classic Hanna takedown, one which sets the tone nicely for the rest of &lt;em&gt;Le Tigre&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s this spirit which lies at the heart of the album, and its strengths. Hanna is at her best as a lyricist when she’s telling you what’s wrong and how it should be. While “Deceptacon” is the standout track of the album, it’s closely followed by “Hot Topic,” a song about pop music that builds up to a “Losing My Edge”-style list of strong female artists that would take ages to explore. Third track “What’s Yr Take On Cassavetes?,” in which the band debates the merit of John Cassavetes, is also memorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album never quite regains the dance-punk spark of the first three tracks, but the rest is still an enjoyable listen, especially for those who can’t get past Bikini Kill’s hardcore influences. Hanna’s spirit and message infuse even the weaker tracks with an energy that carries them to greater heights. Whenever the songs begin to feel bland and uninteresting, Hanna manages to pull out a clever lyric or harsh statement that directs the listener’s attention front and center once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps &lt;em&gt;Le Tigre&lt;/em&gt;‘s greatest trait is its ability to deliver punk spirit entwined with shockingly catchy dance numbers. The album may not be stuffed with conventional dance or punk numbers, but it’s a brilliant and vicious strike against oppression and dull pop that will linger in your head for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spoon - They Want My Soul</title>
      <link>http://333vinyl.us/articles/spoon-they_want_my_soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01  Aug 2014 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://333vinyl.us/articles/spoon-they_want_my_soul/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the few years I was discovering new music on my own, I would play the most recent album on Rdio to see if I liked a band. In 2011, Spoon’s latest was the divisive &lt;em&gt;Transference&lt;/em&gt;. It’s still one of my favorite Spoon albums, and I was never a huge fan of &lt;em&gt;GA GA GA GA GA&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Gimme Fiction&lt;/em&gt; (both enjoyable listens, but neither stood out to me). It took me another few years to discover the breakthrough &lt;em&gt;Kill the Moonlight&lt;/em&gt;, which remains my favorite Spoon album. &lt;em&gt;They Want My Soul&lt;/em&gt;, however, is the now-mature band’s best offering since their career-standout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The album begins with first single “Rent I Pay,” which sets the tone wonderfully for the rest of the album. It’s relatively straightforward but packs the confident groove we’ve come to expect from Spoon. “Inside Out,” a late-night slow-burner (accompanied with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IpT5SBg1Mmk&quot;&gt;trippy video&lt;/a&gt;) follows directly after, creating Spoon’s strongest one-two punch since 2002’s &lt;em&gt;Kill the Moonlight&lt;/em&gt; (“Small Stakes”/“The Way We Get By”). The acoustic guitar/bass/drum combination on the next three tracks prove that Spoon haven’t lost the ability to groove, which was front-and-center on &lt;em&gt;GA GA GA GA GA&lt;/em&gt;, even managing to surpass some of the album’s finest tracks. “Do You,”” in particular, sounds like an improved version of “Don’t You Evah.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half of the album is where Spoon shakes things up a bit. “Outlier” sounds like Arctic Monkeys’ “Fireside” with better lyrical themes and more well-placed digs at Garden State (&lt;code&gt;I remember you walked out of Garden State / You had taste, you had taste, you had taste&lt;/code&gt;). The title track stands out as one of the most “daytime”-sounding tracks an album that sounds most comfortable playing through car speakers late at night. “I Just Don’t Understand” is a great cover that ties in nicely to “Let Me Be Mine”; the latter is some of Britt Daniel’s better plainspoken, more emotional writing. “New York Kiss” completes the sentimental trilogy, ending on a note worthy of the rest of the album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, much of the instrumentation doesn’t stand out, but this is no surprise. Spoon are remarkably consistent. True to form, the way the band combines all their tight, crisp, relatively simple pieces together remains their greatest strength. Some tracks sound quite similar, but repeated listens reveal intricacies that make each track stand out in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;em&gt;They Want My Soul&lt;/em&gt; is one of the year’s best releases so far, providing exciting, intriguing variations on the classic Spoon sound. Do yourself a favor and listen to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>